healthandage.com 2008-10-06

# Aging - Health Topics and Medical News Stories

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for http://healthandage.org's entire web site.  

Privacy Policy

Throughout this Privacy Policy HealthandAge Foundation, , c/o: Prof. Dr. Hannes B. St?helin, Memory Clinic, Schanzenstrasse 55, 4000 Base, Switzerland is referred to as "HAF" or "HealthandAge.com".

**Website Privacy Policy**

By accessing or using HealthandAge.org, you agree to the following terms of the Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy complies with the Swiss data protection legislation when processing information (e.g.: your name, birth date, e-mail address, mailing address etc.) which relates to an identified or identifiable person ("Personal Data"). This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for HealthandAge.org. Further explanation may be provided, where appropriate, on pages where personal data is requested. This Privacy Policy, coupled with any supplementary explanation, is designed to provide privacy protection tailored to the individual visitor to, or user of, HealthandAge.org.

If you do not agree to these terms, please do not access or use HealthandAge.org. 

HealthandAge.org reserves the right to change the Privacy Policy from time to time at its sole discretion without any individual notice. HealthandAge.org will place appropriate notice of this fact on its home page. You shall have the ability to opt-out as per Section 6 below of having your information used in the revised way. 

Each use of HealthandAge.org will be subject to the most current version of the Privacy Policy at the time of such use.   
The current version is dated 1 May 2006   

**1\. Overview**  
By the means of this Privacy Policy, HealthandAge.org intends to notify you of:

  * What Personal Data and other information abut you or third parties is collected from you through HealthandAge.org (Section 2 and 3); 
  * How the Personal Data and other information is used (Section 2, 3 and 4); 
  * What choices are available to you regarding collection, use and distribution of Personal Data (Section 3 and 6); 
  * The types of security procedures that are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of Personal Data and other information under HealthandAge.org's control (Section 5);
  * How you can correct any inaccuracies in or delete your Personal Data (Section 7);
  * The Name and all details of the organization collecting the Personal Data and other information (Section 9 and 10);  

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**2\. Collection of Anonymous Data**   
Most of the information that HealthandAge.org collects is anonymous information, such as the pages you visit and the searches you perform.

**2.1 Log Files**  
HealthandAge.org will record the following information from any visitor going through its site: browser type, IP address, domain name, access time, and operating system. This aggregate data helps HealthandAge.org have a "macro-view" of the visitor traffic and understand what sections of the site the users like most. HealthandAge.org also uses the information to see what kind of technology is available on the visitors' computers so it can better serve them by utilizing more advanced technologies (e.g.: Macromedia Flash). None of this information is linked to any Personal Data.

**2.2 Cookies** **and Advertisements**

_2.2.1 Our Cookies_   
HealthandAge.org may collect other anonymous data regarding your visit to our web site, including, for example, the date and time of your visit, and the domain name of the server from which you are visiting. This can provide HealthandAge.org information which may enable us to improve our web site to best serve you. None of this information is linked to any Personal Data.

_2.2.2 Advertiser Cookies_  
HealthandAge.org engages third parties to assist in placing advertisements on HealthandAge.org. These third parties may also use cookies or other technological means to gather the same anonymous information described in Section 2.2.1. In addition, if you click on an advertisement, these third parties may use these means to gather information regarding the web sites you visit after the HealthandAge.org site. These third parties are not permitted to collect Personal Data from you on HealthandAge.org without your consent, and they are not permitted to link any non-personal cookie information collected by them on HealthandAge.org to Personal Data they or others collect from other sites. However, HealthandAge.org cannot monitor or control the actions of these third parties, and will not be responsible for any actions taken by them. If you do not wish to permit these third parties to gather information from you, you should either go to the third party website and opt-out, configure your browser to block third party cookies, or use a specific tool to do the same. Most browsers are set to automatically accept these cookies. However, you can change your browser's settings to prevent the acceptance of cookies.

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**3\. Collection of Personal Data**

**3.1 Personal Data collected by using HealthandAge.org services**  
HealthandAge.org collects the following Personal Data from users of the following services on its site:

_3.1.1 Newsletter_  
HealthandAge.org registers your e-mail address to be able to send you the newsletter on a regular basis. To opt-out cf. Section 6 below.

_3.1.2 Feedback forms_  
HealthandAge.org collects your e-mail address and comments only. HealthandAge.org will only send a follow-up e-mail to you if you explicitly request us to do so in the "Additional Comments" field. The address will also be used to send you our newsletter if you decide to subscribe to it (see Newsletter). The other information that HealthandAge.org requests in this section is used only to know what articles are most successful on a qualitative basis on the site but without any linking to your Personal Data. HealthandAge.org does not use your information for other purposes unless you explicitly agree to such use at the time of the collection.

_3.1.3 "Suggest to a friend" feature_  
HealthandAge.org uses your name and your friend's e-mail address in order to send him or her a message about the interest of the specific article you are recommending. The data provided is temporarily stored to prevent misuse and will not be used for any other promotional communications.

**3.2 Public Forums Services (freely accessible for everybody)**   
_3.2.1 Senior Meeting Place section_   
To register to the senior meeting database, a user has to provide his or her e-mail address as mandatory information as well as a username and a password. The e-mail address is requested so that other seniors can contact this registrant directly for future communications and is therefore freely accessible for everybody. HealthandAge.org does store the e-mail addresses in a database, but does not intend to use them in any other way. 

Optional Personal Data such as "country, town, and state" can also be entered. This serves other participants in that they know where all the other users come from and whether or not they live close to each other. HealthandAge.org does store this Personal Data in a database, but does not intend to use them in any other way. 

Your personal profile can be modified or deleted by you at any time using the available options "edit" or "delete" (cf. Section 7). 

Since the information you provide at the Senior Meeting Place section is public and accessible to an unlimited number of parties, the respective information may be transferred in countries and jurisdictions with less restrictive or no data protection rules. By submitting your information you hereby expressly consent to such transfers. If you do not want your information made public and accessible to an unlimited number of parties from countries or jurisdictions with less restrictive or no data protection rules, do not participate in the Senior Meeting Place section. 

HealthandAge.org registers your e-mail address to be able to send you the newsletter on a regular basis. To opt-out cf. Section 6 below. HealthandAge.org uses your first name and your friend's e-mail address in order to send him or her a message about the interest of the specific article you are recommending. Your friend's e-mail address is not stored in a database and will not be used for any other promotional communications. 

**3.3 Polls**  
In the case of a poll, Personal Data is usually not requested. However, if some Personal Data happens to be requested, we will only collect the e-mail address of the user and his or her first name in order to be able to follow-up at a later stage with prior permission.

**3.4 Optional Aspect of Collected Information**  
On HealthandAge.org, all Personal Data collected is usually optional and most services remain freely accessible when a user decides not to give out any information to HealthandAge.org. 

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**4\. Processing of Personal Data**

**4.1 Services other than Public Forum Services**  
HealthandAge.org will only process the Personal Data as described in Section 3 of this Privacy Policy. We will not sell, share, or otherwise distribute your Personal Data to third parties without your consent. However, Personal Data may occasionally be transferred to third parties who act for or on behalf of HealthandAge.org, or for further processing in accordance with the purpose(s) for which the data was originally collected. Where such disclosure of Personal Data to a third party occurs, we will endeavor to ensure that the processing is performed in accordance with the purposes and within the limits under which the data was originally collected. If a change entails that HealthandAge.org intends to use the information that a user has given to HealthandAge.org in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, we will not do so unless we get clear and written e-mail permission by the user. Thus, if this situation occurs, HealthandAge.org will pro-actively seek permission prior to any change that can affect the user's privacy.

**4.2 Forum**  
HealthandAge.org makes chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to its users (e.g. the Senior Meeting Place). Please remember that any information (including Personal Data) that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information, and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose personal information. If you do not want your personal information made public and accessible to an unlimited number of parties, specifically from countries or jurisdictions with less restrictive or no data protection rules, do not disclose personal information in Public Forums of HealthandAge.org (regarding the rules of conduct in the respective Public Forum cf. the HealthandAge.org's Terms of Use).

**4.3 Boutique**  
Parties other than HealthandAge.org operate stores, provide services, or sell products, services etc. on this site. In addition, HealthandAge.org may provide links to the sites third parties. HealthandAge.org is not responsible for examining or evaluating, and we do not warrant the offerings of, any of these businesses or individuals or the content of their Web sites. HealthandAge.org does not assume any responsibility or liability for i.e. the actions, products, services and content of all these and any other third parties. You should carefully evaluate such third parties and review their privacy statements and other conditions of use, sale etc.

**4.4 Transfer into Archives and Destruction of Data**  
The collected data will be transferred into an archive at regular intervals. Data which is archived may be destroyed without notice at any time.   
However, HealthandAge.org reserves the unlimited right to destroy collected data at any time and without prior notification.  

**4.5 Distribution of Information to you by HealthandAge.org**  
Our site users can expect to be contacted by HealthandAge.org in the following circumstances if you have not chosen to opt-out as per Section 6 below.   
_  
4.5.1 By email_  
Users who have voluntarily subscribed to our newsletter will receive the Newsletter at regular interval as described on the subscription page or as posted on the site from time to time. Users will not be contacted for any other purpose unless they explicitly request that we do so.   
Users who send a Feedback form (located at the bottom of each article) to HealthandAge.org. . If they explicitly request an answer from HealthandAge.org in the "Additional Comments" field, we will e-mail them with our response.

_4.5.2 By telephone_  
HealthandAge.org will not contact you by telephone, unless expressively disclosed.

**4.6 Surveys**  
HealthandAge.org may, from time to time, conduct polls and surveys. These are conducted solely on HealthandAge.org's web site and by e-mail to Newsletter subscribers. Participation is optional and all services remain accessible for free when a visitor decides not to participate in a poll. Please read the Section 3 to know more about how any collected data is stored and used in the event of a survey.

**4.7 Data Request by Law, by Court or by a Regulatory Authority**  
If required by law, by court or by a regulatory authority HealthandAge.org will make accessible all requested data to such parties.

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

** 5\. Protection of your Personal Data**  
Inside HealthandAge.org only selected employees and contractors have access to the server via their password. Employees and contractors are made aware of the security policy through internal memos on a regular basis or each time a major change to the policy occurs.   
The security policy is reviewed every six (6) months to ensure its accuracy and to ensure that it reflects any changes that have occurred on the web site.   
**Please take into consideration that the World Wide Web is a publicly accessible system. Each time information is made available online this is done at your own risk. Your data might be lost under way or may be accessible to unauthorized third persons.**

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**6\. Choice/Opt-out**  
Our site provides users the opportunity to receive communications from us. This is done at the point where we request information about the visitor.   
This site also gives users the following option for removing their information from our database in order not to receive future communications or to no longer receive our service.   
To unsubscribe from one or more of our newsletters, please click the unsubscribe link at the end of every newsletter edition.and send a mail with Unsubscribe as the subject line. Please detail the name(s) of the newsletter(s) in question. In your correspondence, please accurately indicate your Personal Data (e.g.: your e-mail or mail address). An inaccurate description will cause delay or failure in processing your request.   
Please note that if you provide HealthandAge.org with inconsistent information, HealthandAge.org cannot guarantee that your most recent privacy preference will be honored. 

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**7\. Links**  
This web site contains links to other web sites. Please note that when you click on one of these links, you are 'clicking' to another web site. We encourage you to read the privacy statements of these linked sites as their privacy policy may differ from ours. (see Terms of Use). 

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**8\. Contacting the Web Site**  
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact  
HealthandAge.com Web Team (Privacy Issues)   
HealthandAge Foundation   
Blegistrasse   
CH 6340 Baar, Switzerland  
email: [here](mailto:contact@healthandage.com)

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

**9\. Questions or Concerns regarding this Privacy Policy**  
If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, you should first contact HealthandAge.org's web team by clicking [here](mailto:contact@healthandage.com)

Back to the Table of Contents

* * *

This Privacy Policy was created on 1 May 2006
